Let's take a closer look at linear function approximation and how to
我们来仔细研究下线性函数逼近
estimate the parameter vector w. As you've seen already,
以及如何估算参数向量
a linear function is a simple sum over
你已经知道 线性函数是所有特征乘以相应的权重
all the features multiplied by their corresponding weights.
并求和的结果
Let's assume you have initialized these weights
假设你已经随机初始化这些权重
randomly and computed the value of a state v hat (s,w).
并计算了状态值 v^(s,w)
How would you tweak w to bring the approximation closer and closer to the true function?
如何调整 W 以使逼近函数越来越接近真函数？
Sounds like a numerical optimization problem.
听起来像一个数值优化问题
Let's use gradient descent to find the optimal parameter vector.
我们使用梯度下降来找到最优参数向量
Firstly, note that since v hat is a linear function,
首先注意 因为 v^ 是一个线性函数
its derivative with respect to w is simply the feature vector x(s).
相对于 W 的导数就是特征向量 x(s)
This is a nice thing about linear functions and why they are so popular.
这也是线性函数的优势之一以及为何如此受欢迎的原因
We'll use this shortly.
稍后我们将利用这一点
Now let's think about what we are trying to optimize.
现在思考下我们尝试优化的对象
We said we want to reduce or minimize the difference between
我们想要缩小真值函数 vπ
the true value function v pi and the approximate value function v hat.
和逼近值函数 v^ 之间的差异
Let's write that down as a squared difference,
我们写成平方差
since we are not concerned with the sign of the error and
因为我们不关心误差的符号
we simply want to drive the difference down toward zero.
只想使差异降低到 0
To be more accurate, since reinforcement learning domains are typically stochastic,
更确切地来说 因为强化学习领域通常都是随机的
this is the expected squared error.
这是预期平方差
We now have an objective function to minimize.
现在我们有了要优化的目标函数
To do that using gradient descent,
为此我们将使用梯度下降
let's find the gradient or derivative of this function with
我们来计算该函数相对于 W 的梯度或导数
respect to w. Using the chain rule of differentiation,
使用差分链式法则
we get minus two times the value difference times the derivative of v hat,
结果是 -2 乘以值差异乘以 v^ 的导数
which we earlier noted was simply the feature vector (x,s).
之前我们提到它就是特征向量 (x,s)
Note that we remove the expectation operator here to
注意 我们去掉了这里的期望运算符
focus on the error gradient indicated by a single state s,
侧重于单个状态 s 表示的误差梯度
which we assume has been chosen stochastically.
我们假设状态是随机选择的
If we are able to sample enough states,
如果我们能够抽样足够多的状态
we can come close to the expected value.
则可以非常接近预期值
Let's plug this in to the general form of
我们将这个代入梯度下降更新规则的一般公式
a gradient descent update rule with alpha as a step-size or learning rate parameter.
α 是步长或学习速率参数
Note that the minus half here is just to
注意这里的 -1/2
cancel out the minus two we got in the derivative.
是为了消去导数中的 -2
This is the basic formulation we will use to iteratively reduce the error
我们将使用这个基本公式迭代地降低每个样本状态的误差
for each sample state till the approximate and true function are almost equal.
直到逼近函数和真函数几乎相等
Here's an intuitive explanation of how gradient descent optimizes the parameter vector.
下面直观地解释下梯度下降如何优化了参数向量
In each iteration, you change the weights a small step away from the error direction.
在每次迭代时 朝着误差的相反方向小步地更改权重
So, the feature vector here points out
因此这里的特征向量可以指出
what direction is bad so that we can move away from it.
哪个方向不合适 这样我们就可以远离该方向
So far, we've only been talking about approximating the state-value function.
到目前为止 我们只讨论了逼近状态值函数
In order to solve a model-free control problem, that is,
为了解决不基于模型的控制问题
to take actions in an unknown environment,
即在未知环境中采取动作
we need to approximate the action-value function.
我们需要逼近动作值函数
We can do this by defining
为此 我们可以定义一个
a feature transformation that utilizes both the state and action,
利用状态和动作的特征转换
then we can use the same gradient descent method as we did for the state-value function.
然后使用状态值函数中用到的梯度下降方法
Finally, let's look at the case where we wish
最后 我们看看希望逼近函数
the approximation function to compute all of the action-values at once.
同时计算所有动作值的情况
We can think of this as producing an action vector.
可以看做生成动作向量
For this purpose, we can continue to use the same feature transformation as before,
为此 我们可以继续使用之前的相同特征转换
taking in both the state and action.
传入状态和动作
But now, how do we generate the different action-values?
但是如何生成不同的动作值？
One way of thinking about it is that we are
一种思考方式是
trying to find n different action-value functions,
我们尝试找到 n 个不同的动作值函数
one for each action dimension.
每个动作维度对应一个函数
But intuitively, we know that these functions are related.
但是凭直觉 我们知道这些函数有关联性
So, it makes sense to compute them together.
因此可以同时计算它们
We can do this by extending our weight vector and turning it into a matrix.
为此 我们可以扩展权重向量并转换为矩阵
Each column of the matrix emulates a separate linear function,
矩阵的每列模拟一个单独的线性函数
but the common features computed from the state and
但是根据状态和动作计算的共同特征
action keep these functions tied to each other.
使这些函数相互保持关联性
If we have a problem domain with a continuous state space,
如果我们的问题领域具有连续状态空间
but a discrete action space which is very common,
但是具有离散动作空间 这很常见
we can easily select the action with the maximum value.
我们可以轻松地选择值最大的动作
Without this sort of parallel processing,
没有这种平行处理的话
we would have to parcel each action one by one and then find their maximum.
我们需要挨个解析每个动作 然后找到最大值
If our action space is also continuous,
如果动作空间也是连续的
then this form allows us to output more than a single value at once.
那么这种形式使我们能够同时输出多个值
For example, if we were driving a car,
例如 如果我们在开车
we'd want to control both steering and throttle at the same time.
则希望同时控制方向盘和油门
The primary limitation of linear function approximation is that we
线性函数逼近的主要限制条件是
can only represent linear relationships between inputs and outputs.
我们只能表示输入和输出之间的线性关系
With one-dimensional input, this is basically a line.
对于一维输入 则是一条线
In 2D, it becomes a plane, and so on.
对于二维输入 变成平面 等等
What if our underlying value function has a non-linear shape?
如果底层的值函数是非线性形状呢？
A linear approximation may give a very bad result.
线性逼近可能会产生非常糟糕的结果
That's when we need to start looking at non-linear functions.
这时候就需要开始研究非线性函数了